<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on 3.3 volts electronics</title>
    <link>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on 3.3 volts electronics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSD1306 oled display i2c interface with bus pirate</title>
      <link>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/ssd1306-oled-display-i2c-interface-with-buspirate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/ssd1306-oled-display-i2c-interface-with-buspirate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DS18B20 1-Wire interface with bus pirate.</title>
      <link>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/ds18b20-1-wire-interface-with-buspirate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/ds18b20-1-wire-interface-with-buspirate/</guid>
      <description>Maxim integrated invented 1-Wire and produces some 1-Wire interface integrated circuits too. 1-Wire devices usually are simple and use one pin for data and one pin for ground. however, driving power from the data line (parasite power) has some limitations that is noted in the datasheet. For example, with parasitic power, it takes longer to measure or convert data. Maxim has a good tutorial on 1-Wire. Unfortunately, it is in flash format (who uses flash these days!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set udev rules for bus pirate on Linux</title>
      <link>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/set-udev-rules-for-bus-pirate-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/set-udev-rules-for-bus-pirate-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>USB serial (UART) peripherals show up as ttyUSB on most Linux distros. The first peripheral is ttyUSB0, the second is ttyUSB1 and so on. On Windows os, they are named com1, com2 and &amp;hellip;. If you want to have a constant name for every peripheral, for example, /dev/buspirtae, you can set udev rules. Every USB device has a vendor id and a product id. $lsusb Bus 002 Device 002: ID 05ac:8406 Apple, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is bus pirate and how to connect it to linux</title>
      <link>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/what-is-bus-pirate-and-how-to-connect-it-to-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vahidtaghiloo.github.io/post/what-is-bus-pirate-and-how-to-connect-it-to-linux/</guid>
      <description>The bus pirate is an open source serial terminal bridge developed by Dangerous Prototypes that talks to electronic stuff through the serial port (or USB port). It supports a variety of protocols like 1-wire, I2C, SPI, JTAG, asynchronous serial (UART), raw 2-wire and 3-wire and HD44780 LCD controller. The board is based on a PIC24F microcontroller and has different versions. the current recommended version is 3.6, there is also a version 4 and version 5 (not fully developed yet).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>